firstchoice.co.uk 2011-12-31

# First Choice | Our Policies | Privacy Policy

TUI UK Limited’s Privacy Policy sets out what information we collect, how we collect it, and what we do with it. 

**INFORMATION ABOUT YOU**

**Your Information**  
This refers to a combination of information such as your name, contact details, travel preferences and special needs/disabilities/dietary requirements that you supply us or is supplied to us, including any information about other persons on your booking (“your information”). Your information is collected when you request information from us, contact us (and vice versa) or make a booking. You are responsible for ensuring that other members of your party are aware of the content of our Privacy Policy and consent to your acting on their behalf in all your dealings with us.  
We will update your information whenever we can to keep it current, accurate and complete.   

**  
Our Use of Your Information**  
(1) For the purpose of providing you with our services, including your flight, holiday or insurance, etc., we may disclose and process your information outside the UK/EEA. In order for you to travel abroad, it may be mandatory (as required by government authorities at the point(s) of departure and/or destination) to disclose and process your information for immigration, border control, security and anti-terrorism purposes, or any other purposes which they determine appropriate. These requirements may differ depending on your destination and you are advised to check. Even if not mandatory, we may exercise our discretion to assist where appropriate.

(2) We may collect and process your information for the purposes set out in our registration with the Office of the Information Commissioner, and disclose the same to our group companies for business purposes and also to companies and our service providers who act as “data processors” on our behalf, or to credit and fraud agencies (some of whom are located outside the UK/EEA). These business purposes include administration, providing services (and contacting you where necessary), customer care, service quality, business management and operation, re-organisation/structuring/sale of our business (or group companies), risk assessment, security, fraud and crime prevention/detection, monitoring, research and analysis, marketing, customer purchasing preferences and trends, dispute resolution, credit checking and debt collection. 

(3) Information (such as health or religion) may be considered “sensitive personal data” under the Data Protection Act 1998. We collect it to cater to your needs or act in your interest, and we are only prepared to accept sensitive personal data on the condition that we have your positive consent. By booking with us you also agree for your insurers, their agents and medical staff to disclose relevant information and sensitive personal data to us in circumstances where we need to act on your behalf or in the interest of passengers or in an emergency. 

**If you do not agree to Our Use of Your Information above, we cannot do business with you or accept your booking.**

**Direct Marketing Material**   
(1) We may from time to time contact you with information on offers of goods and services, brochures, new products, forthcoming events or competitions from our holiday divisions and our group companies. Our websites will assume you to agree to e-communications when you make a booking. 

(2) You may indicate your preference regarding receiving third party direct marketing material.

(3) If do not wish to receive such information or would like to change your preference, please refer to point (2) of “Your Rights” below.   

**Your Rights**  
(1) On completing our Data Subject Access Request form, you are entitled to a copy of the information we hold about you (for a £10 fee) and to correct any inaccuracies. 

(2) You have the right to ask in writing not to receive direct marketing material from us. If available, you can amend your previous preference on our website(s), use our “unsubscribe email” or refer to our literature containing instructions. Once properly notified by you, we will take steps to stop using your information in this way.

(3) For a list of our group companies or brands, please send us your request.  
Please write to TUI UK Limited, Legal Department, TUI Travel House, Crawley Business Quarter, Fleming Way, Crawley, West Sussex RH10 9QL.  

**Foreign Controls**   
Outside the European Economic Area (EEA), note that controls on data protection in such countries may not be as strong as the legal requirements in this country.

**USE OF TOOLS/"COOKIES" AND LINKS TO OTHER WEBSITES**

If our contact and dealing with you is via our website(s), we may use HTTP cookies. These cookies allow us to identify your computer but not you personally.

You can set your web browser to refuse cookies. However, you may not be able to enjoy all the facilities or book via our website if you do so.

**We may use information we hold and cookies to identify your individual website behaviour, searches, preferences, facilitate your activities on our website(s) and provide you with services and offers. For example:-**  
*If you are making a purchase, we may also use cookies to keep track of the transaction from one web page to another.  
*We collect information relating to customer use, trends and patterns and use cookies and software tools to capture, measure and analyse site usage and related information.   
*If you also receive our email marketing, we will tailor the information we send you unless you tell us not to. This will enable us to send you more personalised and relevant communications. You will be given the opportunity on every communication to opt-out of this personalisation.  
*When you are on our website, we may interact with you and/or provide you with personalised information. We do this by using cookies to identify your individual website behaviour which allows us to provide you with more relevant personalised promotions.

When you are online but off our site, to help us deliver advertising effectively and avoid repeating adverts, we employ cookies. These cookies allow us to provide advertising off site which is more relevant to a user’s interests. The information that we collect and share is anonymous and not personally identifiable. It does not contain a user’s name, address, telephone number or email address.

Use of our website(s) is subject to our [Website Terms and Conditions](http://www.firstchoice.co.uk/our-policies/terms-of-use/) of use, which means you agree to our Statement on Cookies.

To find out more about the types of cookies we use and why we use them, please visit view our [Statement on Cookies ](http://www.firstchoice.co.uk/our-policies/statement-on-cookies/index.html)

By using our website(s), you consent to our use of cookies as set out above. Our website(s) may contain links to other sites not controlled by us. It is your responsibility to check the status of these sites. 

**MONITORING**

To ensure that we carry out your instructions accurately, improve our service and for security, we may monitor and/or record: (1) telephone calls; (2) activities using CCTV in and around our premises; and (3) transactions and activities on our website. All recordings are and shall remain our sole property.

**SECURITY STATEMENT**

We have taken all reasonable steps and have in place appropriate security measures to protect your information. 

**CHANGES TO THE POLICY**

Any changes to this Policy will be either on our website, in our brochure and/or made available on request. 

Privacy Policy: v March 2011

**DATA NOTICES:-**

**-Customer Data:** To provide your holiday and ensure that it runs smoothly, we (and your travel agent, if you use one) need to use information such as your name and address, special needs, dietary requirements, etc. Please be informed that we must pass it to suppliers of your travel arrangements, including airlines, hotels and transport companies; we may also supply it to security or credit checking companies, and to public authorities such as customs and immigration. When you make this booking, you consent to this information being passed to the relevant people. Information held by your travel agent is subject to that company’s own data protection policy.

**-Caricom API Data:** Please note that some or all of the Caricom states listed below have entered into an agreement with the USA whereby advance passenger data, required by and provided to Caricom states for border security purposes, will be passed to the USA Department for Homeland Security for processing on behalf of those Caricom states listed as follows: Anguilla, Antigua and Barbuda, The Bahamas, Barbados, Belize, Bermuda, British Virgin Islands, Cayman Islands, Dominica, Grenada, Guyana, Haiti, Jamaica, Montserrat, Saint Lucia, St Kitts and Nevis, St Vincent and the Grenadines, Surinam, Trinidad and Tobago, Turks and Caicos Islands. Collectively members or associate members of ‘Caricom’. The UK Information Commissioner’s Office has accepted that this will not breach the Data Protection Act but that we are required to bring this to your attention. 

- **US Secure flight Data:** The Transportation Security Administration (TSA) requires you to provide your full name, date of birth ,and gender for the purpose of watch list screening, under the authority of 49 U.S.C. section 114, the Intelligence Reform and Terrorism Prevention Act of 2004 and 49 C.F.R parts 1540 and 1560. You may also provide your Redress Number, if available. Failure to provide your full name, date of birth, and gender may result in denial of transport or denial of authority to enter the boarding area. TSA may share information you provide with law enforcement or intelligence agencies or others under its published system of records notice. For more on TSA privacy policies, or to review the system of records notice and the privacy impact assessment, please see the TSA Web site at [www.tsa.gov](http://www.tsa.gov/).
